-The there are two central things that start on r - knights and religion.
After the fall of the Roman Empire, it is messy in Europe.
Although the people here-
-Not seem to have any problems with being carved with sword-
-So it brings changes.
The kings find it harder to educate and pay all the warriors they need.
They give a piece of ground to the knights-
-In exchange for the knights setting up and defending the kingdom.
It is part of the feudal system-
-Where the king gives away some of his power in exchange for loyalty.
The second R made even more mark on its time.
Everything in the Middle Ages has a religious dimension.
All the ancient gods, such as Zeus, Apollon, Oden and Tor retired-
-And there will be new stars in the sky.
In Europe, Christianity goes from having been prohibited to dominating-
In the first circle we find the mildest sinners-
-And at the bottom, on the ground floor nine, the worst.
There we find, for example.
traitor like Judas and brutus-
-Fast frozen in eternal ice.
After the tour through hell it carries off the mountain of the purgatory ...
... before Dante reaches his final destination - paradise.
My first contact with the divine comedy ...
... was when I was nine years old ...
... on a visit home with Grandma and grandfather in Gothenburg.
The pictures from hell caught me the most.
Horrible pictures of devils who torment poor sinners-
Who wants to roll stones or burn in open graves?
"Do as the church says, otherwise it happens."
That it was written on verse made it a little difficult to read it-
-But it was interesting too.
It was written a little more poetically and it was very descriptive.
They flowed better into the text.
It was reminiscent of when I was smaller and read the hobby of Tolkien.
It creates a picture of what it looked like.
The whole description of what happens ...
... if you have sinned and what happens in hell ...
It draws up a horrific picture of how terrible it is-
-As an attempt to make it sound nasty, I would guess.
It's most bizarre.
It's imaginative.
One reason why the book becomes so popular is-
-That it is written in a language that people are actually talking.
It was sensational.
In addition to exciting stories, the knight novels are a label book-
-For noblemen who will learn the knight's ideal.
They would both entertain and raise.
So maybe literature has always been-
-But it is clear in the knight's novel.
The knight novels also contain so -called
Hovish love.
The idea is that a knight should flirt passionate with ladies-
-But be a gentleman and not let it go beying further than crazy looks.
Hövish love is central to one of the most famous novels-
-Tristan and Isolde.
Join us in the relationships now.
Tristan is one of King Artur's knights around the round table.
He is also a sister to King Mark.
-The crusade knight you otherwise associate with the Middle Ages.
Europe's Christians are worried that Muslims will take over Jerusalem.
A French Pope launches the idea of a pilgrimage to save the city.
You equip special knights with a mantle with a large cross on.
Then they are obliged to go to these places-
-and complete his knight service in the crusade.
But the crusades are not an exciting adventure in a romantic shimmer.
What is sold as travel to save Christian sacred sites-
-In bloody conquest war that lasts for hundreds of years.
They move out-
-And pure massacres on especially Jews and Muslims.
There are terrible stories where one cleans cities on folk-
-And cut the throat of infants.
The knight's ideals that the novels have taught no longer apply.
An honorary culture has developed around the knights on the battlefield.
They fought against those who were not Christians.
Unfortunately, many conflicts are founded during the Middle Ages.
The crusade time is still invoked politically, in a clumsy way.
At the end of the Middle Ages, a book is written by two German monk-
-Som, even though it is banned almost immediately, has major consequences.
During the 1400-1600s, a book sells almost as well as the Bible ...
... and it's Malleus Maleficarum - "Witch Hammer".
The witch hammer is a book in three chapters on what a witch is-
-How witchcraft and sorcery go to and how to find and prosecute a witch.
It is an instruction manual in witch hunt-
-And becomes the basis for the witch processes.
The majority that was convicted were women.
According to the book, women are more receptive to the devil's attraction.
Above all, the woman's sexuality is described as threatening.
A completely unscientific perception-
-As has influenced the view of women until today.
Nevertheless, the negative image of the Middle Ages has almost disappeared.
The knight novel had an exaggerated, romantic picture of the knight's life-
-And today we have an excessive romantic picture of the Middle Ages.
What is exciting about the knight novel is-
-The knight's novel is the source of our modern fantasy tradition.
The story of the ring, Narnia and maybe even
Game of Thrones ...
The knight novel is there in the background-
-And is crucial to especially the growth of fantasy.
The crusades are also extensively portrayed.
Every year Ivanhoe is shown on TV ...
... and we also got our own Swedish crusade hero - Arn.
Although the Middle Ages remain in popular culture-
-In computer games, music videos, role-playing and festivals-
-and some love to pretend to live then-
-So you should probably be glad it is just on pretend.
The Middle Ages are interesting to study but you do not want to live that way.
It can be fun to dress up and loop Middle Ages-
-But one would not want to be burned on the bonfire-
-To question whether communion is Jesus' body.
Texting: Henrik Johansson www.btistudios.com